♪The night wind shakes off
the withered leaves♪
♪I open the window and gaze at the moon♪
♪Haze spreads across the river,
lanterns drifting♪
♪I hear the memories rustling♪
♪Garden flowers shed petals one by one♪
♪Candlelight flickers,
swaying with melancholy♪
♪I sigh by the lamp over the long night♪
♪Past memories unfold scene by scene♪
♪It's all your face♪
♪Boldly trampling over my heart♪
♪Two measures of ink I take,
one for love miswritten♪
♪And another for youth passed♪
♪With endless sorrow,
I once traced your silhouette♪
♪Two measures of ink I take,
one for joy and sorrow♪
♪And another for parting and reunion♪
♪I write until splendor fades,
and I am no more♪
=Prelude of the White Snake=
=Episode 15=
Suzhen, Qing,
protect Aunt.
Fahai and I will clear a path.
Hold on.
Stay and protect Suzhen and Aunt.
With his so-so skills,
I'd better do it.
Watch out!
If you want them to live,
come with me quietly.
Forget about me. Protect Aunt.
Suzhen!
Aunt is the priority.
A mere mortal like you,
and you think you can catch me?
You've finally dropped the act.
So you are indeed after me.
Of course I'm after you,
snake demon.
You know?
You're not Changming. You're a demon.
Enough talk.
Right here's fine.
This place is secluded.
The pursuers will take a while.
We can rest a bit.
Fahai, Qing,
take care of Aunt.
I'm saving Suzhen now.
No need.
Suzhen is blessed with luck.
She'll be fine.
Miss Bai is beautiful and kind.
The Buddha will protect her.
Xu Xian, don't worry.
How can I not go?
Miss Bai is just a mortal.
How could she take Changming's torture?
If I'm any later,
I can't imagine what state she'll be in.
It's not certain who's torturing who.
What do you mean?
Why would Changming
capture Miss Bai? Right?
Obviously, she's bait
to lure you into a trap.
His target is you.
He probably won't hurt Miss Bai for now.
What are you doing?
Use your head, will you?
Ringing that bell now
will only expose us
and put Aunt in danger again.
What we need to do now
is check Aunt's injuries
and get some rest ourselves.
Qing.
Is that all you've got?
I thought you'd be tougher.
(No, I can't go back like this.)
I took a wrong turn.
Get back here.
I-I-I don't know how
I offended you, miss.
You look pretty clever.
Miss, I-I-I'd be a terrible meal.
I'm tough when raw,
won't soften either way,
and taste awful.
How about I find you
a tastier one, alright?
I'm not hungry.
I just need a favor from you.
A favor?
Come here.
I'm not coming.
(Myriad Demons House)
It's the lord's handwriting.
Let's go. Miss Bai is locked up.
Wait.
What if it's a trap?
Trap or not, I'm going.
Miss Bai was taken because of me.
I can't just stand by.
Alright, let me hide Aunt first.
What's with this?
Why is everyone so hasty?
I have to hide Aunt first, don't I?
Wait for me.
How long is this going to take?
I should've come back later.
Suzhen's ruse is really something.
She could totally defeat Changming.
Why would she stir up all this drama?
What do you know?
This is called a hero saving the beauty.
Wait for us.
Suzhen!
Xu Xian, get out of here.
It's a trap.
It took you so long.
I thought you wouldn't dare
show up today.
Changming,
what exactly do you want?
Xu Xian, you've foiled my plans
too many times.
Today, none of you are leaving.
You and what army?
Young Master Xu, this wretch
is a disgrace to Jinshan Temple.
Leave him to me.
You go save Miss Bai.
A useless disciple
who can't even wield an artifact?
You're not leaving either.
Xu Xian, look out!
Are you alright?
I was careless.
Just admit you lost.
No need for excuses.
Look after Suzhen.
Let's go.
My lord,
my mission is complete.
Aunt is weak.
I'll take her home first.
I'll go with you.
Suzhen, I'm coming with you too.
No, you don't.
You rest up first.
If we leave the mural like this,
it might stir more trouble.
I must tell my master
to seal the entrance.
Let's split up.
- You...
You go first.
Maybe you should go first.
Miss Bai,
I'm sorry I put you through that
while saving Aunt.
Thank you, on behalf of Aunt.
So, what did you want to say?
Miss Bai,
I'm sorry you were frightened.
Go back and get some rest.
Well, you should go rest too,
Young Master Xu.
Call me if you need anything.
Suzhen, you never used
to stare at the mirror so much.
Is it because of Xu Xian?
Yes, I need to make him love me more.
Now that Aunt is rescued,
and Xu Xian has feelings for you,
can we move forward
as the Goddess instructed?
Yes, so how do we move forward?
According to mortal customs,
it's marriage, of course.
Once you two are united
and pass the love trial,
you can ascend to immortality.
Right, once we achieve that,
we can ascend to immortality.
Qing, thank you.
I never thought Changming
would use Jinshan Temple's name
to commit evil deeds out there.
Luckily, you discovered it in time
and cleared Jinshan Temple's name.
You've done well.
I dare not claim credit.
Master, there's likely more
to what Changming did.
I will investigate it further.
Within the mural is its own world.
Let those demons
live their lives inside.
Cast the spell with me
and seal the entrance.
- Yes.
♪I also gave my youth to someone♪
♪I must admit, you made the journey♪
♪When loving you
became instinct, what's left♪
♪Seals a fate too brutal to amend♪
♪Clumsy and new, we gave our first kiss♪
♪Never thought passionate eyes
would turn cold♪
♪I thought of pulling away,
but I'd barely begun♪
♪Having loved you so deep,
how could I love another♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I'm stubborn,
I never stopped you from loving others♪
♪I shouldn't have been so foolish
to think there was still hope♪
♪But you won't even admit what we had♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I have questions,
I never questioned you♪
♪I'll lock you away and set myself free♪
♪After all, I'm the one you deny♪
♪Having ever loved♪